<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home on Chiara Aina</title>
    <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home on Chiara Aina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chiaraaina.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>bayesian updating</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/more/bayesian_updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/more/bayesian_updating/</guid>
      <description>a short post about Bayesian updating</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post-truth &amp; co.</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/more/post_truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/more/post_truth/</guid>
      <description>a collection of resources on post-truth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>other</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/more/other/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/more/other/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frustration and anger in the Ultimatum game: An experiment</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/publications/frustration_anger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/publications/frustration_anger/</guid>
      <description>Is it possible to persuade others only by providing interpretations of future events? I study the general problem of manipulating a boundedly rational agent by controlling her interpretation of signals she is about to receive. Persuasion arises because the agent updates her beliefs and takes an action based on the narrative she finds most plausible given her prior beliefs. Leveraging this, not only is the persuader able to strategically manipulate the agent to maximize his expected utility, but he can also induce the agent to hold non Bayes-plausible beliefs across signal realizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Stories</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/tailored_stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/tailored_stories/</guid>
      <description>To what extent is it possible to manipulate beliefs by providing interpretations of unknown events? I characterize the feasible posteriors across signals when the agent is exposed to a set of models to interpret observable signals and adopts the model that best fits what is observed. Because each signal could trigger the adoption of a different model, posteriors across signal realizations might not average to the prior. The scope of persuasion is large, even for a persuader who does not control or know the signal the agent observes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contingent Belief Updating</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/contingent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/contingent/</guid>
      <description>We study how contingent thinking – that is, reasoning through all possible contingencies without knowing which is realized – affects belief updating. According to the Bayesian benchmark, beliefs updated after exposure to new information should be equivalent to beliefs assessed for the contingency of receiving such information. Using an experiment, we decompose the effect of contingent thinking on belief updating into two components: (1) hypothetical thinking (updating on a piece of not-yet-observed information) and (2) contrast reasoning (comparing multiple contingencies during the updating process).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weighting Competing Narratives</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/weighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/weighting/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to understand how we update beliefs in the presence of competing narratives. It is common to be in situations where we are uncertain about how the data we observe was generated: different competing narratives could explain the data. How do people learn in these settings? Do they select only one narrative to update beliefs, or do they form posteriors that place non-zero weights on all narratives? Selecting only one narrative leads to more extreme beliefs, while weighting different narratives allows for more nuanced conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing in Tailores Stories</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/competing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/research/competing/</guid>
      <description>We study the competition among senders in the supply of models. For example, politicians compete to supply voters with models to interpret data on immigration or economic outcomes; brokers might want clients to interpret the same firm’s performance differently, driven by different incentives. The senders&amp;rsquo; strategies and the receiver&amp;rsquo;s beliefs vary with respect to the incentives of the parties involved</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://chiaraaina.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiaraaina.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
